just put the uh... lecture sixty notes
online
like ten minutes ago
purposes
they see a continuation uh...
philosophize
so we're gonna keep going on dot blot
lube
by-products
look some more at the g_p_s_ data
and back pain in a cloud right now is
working on the dataset for us where he's
got three g_p_s_ is up on the roof
on a big bar and they are today
raised up
and the idea is to compared the accuracy
of the three different u_p_s_'s
recording the same sky
over a few days each going through a few
steps and see if we can actually uh...
distinguished the vertical difference
between each of those steps
and see how each of the g_p_s_ is doing
they're at
supreme radically different ups and
celebration sees the results of
accurately
we think we know what's gonna happen
but
to give a shot
all right so we didn't create myself by
noon
class sixteen
directory if you don't already have it
aminika rejects
file from last time
the datafile karen
so under examples
way down here in the giant mess of stuff
chippy examples
and we're going to get the two thousand
eleven
gta jot down
speaking to you that that you get
and that's a graph the data
or you can you assess and around
so it's this
third one down here
uh... t_g_a_ dot that appeasing
right-click on it to the link and then
you can do
but let me get command in the directory
wanted to be in xp or
clicking signature classics
it looks very strange
so their examples directory down below
yet
if he's grown so that
isn't
and say i saw a new orders so then
right-click on that
two thousand one and unit and prevented
retreat
so it's opening
they're stuck
suzuki final
close uh...
images of a very good book your terminal
control you
quickly if that works too
canceling the same thing is backing up
type explore
x and then chaotic l
patricia changed
click on this window
and it's gonna kill it
so at skill is a as a commands that if
you want some to go away for sure
it's pretty effective
so keep running ads all agreements are
gone and then
so there are going to be stockbrokers
who do extra on all of them
and that could help them
don't try this if your machine is
working right
expel
is a program
which euro using was called the x window
system is the display thing they handled
windows in which it's and whatnot
it's called x eleven
and when does the term windows before
microsoft windows meant something
completely different
x kills
changes your cursor to relax support if
the system set up for a little strong
crossbow nsn
the next window that you clicked on
will get destroyed very aggressively
it will in fact detach it from the
screen and it just goes to prove
so if i could be max is completely
stockton something's going wrong
uh... you can run x kill
no options
the purchase changes be very careful
what you click on next because whenever
you put on mexico's by so when you click
it just works one cigarette and a couple
of the times question
some of the process will get stock
with specific software that's chances
for things to get completely wedged
in some regard case that's part of its
offer twelve percent figure out
if that happens is the way on alexis
into destroyer ticket program torture
and there's other ways to do it but this
is the way you guessed it
if you see the window and seeing it
happen exported to die
it's it's really aggressive
the two thousand eleven ten at eleven
gta
dot that yet
prime minister over kind of from my
father werner
go through great effort to make and just
because
seating functions being written willful
times is not a bad thing
summer start from scratch
indymac swing there
inside of
sixteen-year artery
three as we do is just to to control x
control half
and then down here just type if you've
got a classic steen maiden
since i don't have it be showing up
there may have a g to refresh
different record it mode and you'll see
the data file appear
amanda keep going through the
exponential arrest the semester if they
are tired of hearing the menu shut down
familiar control x two
so i can keep it around
control x control at cameron recall
wonder
primarily with the number two
just so in case anyone is
confused between lecture fifteen lecture
sixteen
won't hurt you dot pine
catch up to where we were last time
summer start with the basic
beginning of the scripts
usurping cnv
papon
we're gonna import the models that we're
gonna use
sewing and imports pipe raj
this is art
power projection
slash
geometry on our sphere
green circle distance
we're also going to use num pride
for a raise and our expulsion
again we need is that it leah saddam by
as and keys so we can refer to it is
empty
amma to bring into more that i'll be
using later on
sets
and show you something slightly
different here
that you can say call ma
and a couple different libraries
so we're gonna have thesis and the ls
models coming in here
but if you want to use them later on
we'll see how we're doing a mother not
unlike you gotta go
so let's go ahead and start treating our
wonder but function again sold out
is the beginning of the definition of
function then when give the name
so wonder underscore list
and file name
so this is our function name
and then this is going to be a list of
are going to just have one ran across in
the file in the warm-up open
and will start off
to sprint
working on
file colin
file name
this is not in the notes
but this is something i typically do
when writing software
so that i know that the function i meant
to start
and you'll see a lot of programmers put
elope written statement the beginning of
a function and i pray at the end of the
function
and then when you run the code you can
see dysfunction start and stop
and it is kind of movie bugging trick
with megan for the better in this class
later on but typically you can depart
program just by putting print statements
inside of the code and watching the
stuff perhaps screen
say that
camberley go ahead and just run that
basic little part first picture perfect
image it could
adjusted g down here without the control
and are now seem i wondered too dot five
here
been talking to people trying to figure
out
whether or not that's dash dash pile up
stuff is good or bad
i didn't like it
but i was rendered to follow the
people's convention and i'm gonna give
up on dash dash file out
and we'll see how i can
i might have to
revert back to trying it out to see what
happens so i'm going to say
high-profile
and i'm not gonna give it the dash dash
pile at this time
miserable is is that
it import the bunch of stuff it doesn't
tell us
so then
well later on like we try to find
low-tax were to come from
it's very confusing to follow
uh... we've had a number of people vote
for not doing that anymore because and
they tried to follow that the notes
and give it a go it didn't really work
so there's
i fight on amorous saying ls make sure
we've got our border chewed up i was
sitting right in there
and we can go ahead imports wondered
into u dot
import one or two
and our broader module and
just as a reminder
from now on what you were in the first
time and i fight on for bed after you
need to reload it when you make changes
sold
just to show you reload
and that will bring it
in eighteen
so let's go ahead and say
wander and see what's in
so go back to your team x window and
i'll show you
which in essence
in this in one little tiny bit of
punctuation there's a comma
inbetween blistering
and the bombing
receiving prints and i have really
explain too much about print
will start getting into prints and fancy
string stuff
number as we need really really need it
so hopefully if you do that men do worry
about it should work to feed you
leader of one or two
you'll see
wonder list and then your other
modules that you brought in there
so we can say
water to utah
wanderlust
and then we can give it a file name
so will say single quote to zero
and then press tab
and complete that file name so it looked
in the current directory
and founder of the matching prominent
give it to us
this is why i love i put on
if you press answer
it's now going to give us a little print
statement
and should say print
there would be a working on file poland
and then are following
so credible that have
the program tell you if you're going
have you imported your module
so important wonder
typo as
secu appears to be done
out there
important impact hasn't peed
and then imports is
is not is that's cool that's operating
system
first two years and module
uses is and visit common on appearance
did
if i make the point that it bigger
cerebellum right but it's hard to people
as nineteen zero reload
go back through and watch the classes
and pay particular attention to wear
that killed a is used
if he gets all confusing because that's
an alias typically
but you back to print to file names
so let's go back through the projection
sovereignty
so we need to you
create geo object
mahe enter
and remember
email x's your friend in terms of the
indentation for python
when i was at the end here
and i hit enter
invented four spaces for me
automatically
let it do that for you
and if you don't have the right
indentation during here you compressed
cabinet will take you to the right spot
typically sergio d
equals
every state park proj
dot and then chap capital g_e_ odi
for the actual clustering using and was
that you let
people's carried yes
eighty four
there's anybody remember what debbie
just eighty four is
if you look so it yet
that the sales of used in the g_p_s_
system
so that's a victory does this do you
know the object that we can use to do
conversion between
to point to get the great circle
distance and direction
so now we need to load the data now if
you ever last time we talked about the
load t x t commands
it's not found right now could you vote
e_s_t_ question
by not doing dash espy lab we didn't
bring in things like low-tax into this
default space
summer have two important
i'm hoping will help you guys
remember more about where attacks came
from so when you try to write code with
that you'll find it
to get the directions we have to say
import
num buying as
but we have writer here
what have you had same bang
children try this
so now if we do and he
protect melody and then tab
you see a couple different options
talks here on this coming here
so this gives us the three options that
could be and mode t x t is one of those
city extn alexa new question mark
when you hit enter you'll get the help
for low-tax
so now that should be cute i remind you
that low taxes coming from the num on
module
please scroll down you can see all the
different options explained
and for example or going to be using
unpack
with this x_y_z_ comma style
unpacking budgetary bolts political head
and
put that in here
would be just like last time
comma why thomas e
and if you don't remember the file
what's in there we can say alice into
you
bang to run of ash commands
easy catch
and then two thousand eleven
so i'm gonna go ahead and make this big
per second signal see it
so the escalation point in here
says i want to run abacha shell command
so what we're back in the old show but
we start off with
and that's where we can run to be easy
cac anh em we could have run from it
terminally-ill regularly and then we
can't describe the first headlines with
head
the nice thing is
by to see you guys bash
it doesn't just go away with his first i
i thought it was just
hides behind the escalation point
historian characters
so you can still get those commands and
use them
if you want to know
so this is his is the first ten lines of
that
and in there
i have a comment for the first
lina tells us what the fields are
and if somebody gives you
if it doesn't have that first-line yes
maximum has found that you file
an actual hairline in there
services do you telling us what he could
be sculpted to export as they were only
care about the s
could go back to our team x window we
can say
now we know that we have x_y_z_
quality satellites and each dot
so keep it
but those yet quality
missus commas between
satellites
he'd stop
equals in our knees are loaded
experience
and the first thing you give it is a
file name
and that's good
be passed in
through
the arguments the function
will say
file name
and then we need to say on crack
equals
which which is the way they are impacted
in the forest service lecture program
out you can't do that
yep that's exactly
same exif ridiculed for their
yeah it's typically
i actually know what you don't even need
that
if you could do three points but you can
just if there's parentheses it'll just
work
superior three dots
and that's actually about
scissors and open plant the seed
obviously enter
just like that
that's pretty here's more decision and
stuff so
my family
is not a cure but the indentation
because you're inside the plant the
seeds
gifting you can do is make your imax
wider and just write long lines is often
communion
so let's go ahead and try that will say
that with control x control us
trucks control s
member there's no stars down here
emo career on this and make it smaller
so you guys can see that again
silicone is going on
and i liked your echoed in really small
chunks
so i write a liar to i'd try to run it i
see what happens
because if you write
so you have the bonds of coding and unit
run
when i was going to happen in there if
you might have
fifty different errors
in a related in some of them might be
just typos and some of them might be
you put together a kind of a funny way
and then you have to go back and rewrite
for his feelin so it's nice to starting
small chunks if you can
soldier reload
wonder
thanks have their again
and that reloaded and now we can try to
run the command identified rope apparel
to find it
so there was the commands
and hopefully this will just run without
causing troubles
i really have a problem
so if you ever the low text
was coming from this non-pilot stuff
tonight
didn't do it so trend of all this weird
style
is causing the problems too
so i imagine it's public of you guys the
troubles needed
and pete period in there
to bring it in from that
modules so that this way
by not doing this magical bring
everything in
and not nor comes
when you're looking for documentation on
low tax you know to look for an umpire
to continue on the high fine
to save back
rewrote it
and then the rewrite
bring our function doing our motivated
then
status that we didn't disappears
but at least is running correctly
so hopefully
everybody hit enter they got a little
printout
let's go ahead and have a function at
the end
the says print
loading
and then filed
flats again a common here
so by doing that one is done loading the
data rather than just returned to prompt
and you don't know
where you went through this were to get
your sense of where you left
that function
so as to the controllers wanda hyper
directory we don't really need that
anymore
let's go ahead and try to calculate the
centroid of all of our points for voting
on zach's is unwise
america wrap this morning
so they can play with it
on the terminal against look at it
atpase to enter here
we need to change the file name to be
our file
two thousand eleven
pressed captain finished that out
duel of
that way we have a data in a ride python
shell to play with and try out
our commander to look through them
so the first time in grandview if
calculate the average uh...
at those so we need to do you have a
rich
for for now it's hiding behind and pizza
and peas
average
and then acts and this is going to
calculate the average value of all those
actions that are in there
happiness lose out of five point four
slight
senior props with here
uh...
subrident thirty mins
when that we have to vote i think there
was a
typhoon to go back to your
terminal survival coming in
okay import here wonder too
now have the authority
iran dante dot average
on acts
so if you take clues
the center
see how you have all those variables
from so now you have to say and he died
aberration silent commands
went live coverage
and then a acts
unexpected indentation of payments
online sorry
we control any building in airline he's
leaving a message dated him
so you have an actual space and all of
your lines
contracts signed you have it
i don't think that fix something
while
that was better
uh... my lips stuff
my i had an safely
is
uh... dan
it said program intermediate always
around it mattered is that i am so
stress and click here
did call for me
that isn't unfortunate
behavior do near you got it thanks so
much baby
still victory doctor problem one
and technical analysts
yet you mispel ellipse it doesn't just
give you an air it picks up a whole
program which is really a bag so you
have to start exactly like that
or you get completely
i think i'm in a file that is a bug to
the proj
author and say please don't just throw
us out completely
so that we've got discovered a nice
little bug infy proj
this is an avenue my code
to do
file
reports
left author
that's a no for me for later
case that went down
so good job guys find that blood in
figuring out what it was
uh... not always very much fun
so now what we have are point slowed up
record for everybody let's go ahead and
use that have rich function that we had
over here
serena say
exit out
equals and p dot average
of acts
and why have equals and p dot average
note at first what time
it's worth repeating
capitation center expensive the take
time
using you're trying to use the computer
make it didn't work for us but
if we cut that the average of eighty
thousand points every time we went
through it
it's a bit turns into a very large
number of calculation so if you can cut
this i mean one since it into a very
well
there's generally a good thing
so now we need to live through
all of our data
this is one thing that's where it's
classic of
computer scientist isn't necessary the
most friendly
we tend to use a height is our counter
through lists of things
it's not very intuitive until you see in
everybody's code thousand times
so you can see it might go to
it might be better to call something
else but i called up i my notes on the
stick with my own oh it's not
transcript
tourists a range of life
acts let's try to over here on a lot
so we're working with this for a great
down here
you member the range command
with the range of five
it's going to count zero three four
but we can also say we'd like a list of
all the numbers that
is the length uh...
our rate actually can say
julius a length of accidents tells us
the length of the year a acts
so eighty six thousand points in our
rate
ever i don't want to look at every
single point and how to write so we need
a list of those who can save range
now i get enter
you're gonna see a lot of numbers go
screaming by
so i'm gonna go ahead and enter and then
i'll bring back the commands you can see
it again
there were a six thousand numbers across
the screen
thirty years this to walk across
are always
so that we go back over here we've got
are for a loop
it's going to walk in here is always
going to go through each value in our
l_a_ and we can now say
d equals
d_o_d_ dot inverse
x have
why i have
marie did so i will explain to you with
all the parts are
so where are you
this g g_o_t_ object
worries the inverse which is gonna take
two different longitudinal attitude
ended up computers that direction from
the first one to the second one
the second one first one thirty two for
directions and they give us the distance
in the years between the two
so we've taken our average
four centuries point of this cloud of
points
as our first point
and then we've got into our x-ray
through the eyes
pointed out with trap the wires radii
point to go with it so if you think
about
your race
of numbers
so we have our acts list in our wireless
and we have at this in zero some number
at one we have some number some number
to you
that's going to go on down say you know
ten thousand
that some number at some numbers that
were out these pairs sits in a grab a
acts and that while value out of their
and use them to calculate the distance
to our effort at this
blob of points
we have excelled
comma white houses are
century uh... this
massive
influx
bring to get back
something that's
kind of a funky and i'm gonna go just
another quick example to see it so i'm
gonna do
pace considering
important hai proj try it out
mimicry one of these objects
metadata need a copy
and the pace that in there
groups to do that
g_m_t_ equals pi approach dot g_e_
indeed
you look he calls
to beat yes
g_e_ o d dot inverse
concerning
x zero wise zero
minus
warren
boss point
why minus one since an example we did
last time
so what we're doing here is we're just
doing it wants to see what we get back
to make sure we understand the output
so this is going to be our direction
into grease
but at the back for stretching and
agrees
and then this is the distance in meters
between the two points
so what we want to do is take this d
very well which contains
this list of three things
and grab the part that wanna keep
so we need to be building
a list of our directions and our
differences so we need to go and creates
a list of organ add to so will say delta
direction
fishing in direction
equals and we're gonna make it empty
left
so nothing in it
emerged as are added to the end of it
and delta
and for many years
and also identified sentiment u_s_-iraqi
batting point in the end of those
this is going to be our results of their
return back
so whatever term goes back at the end
were done
but the bottom will save return
delta
turcotte mine
c_q_ returning a number of items back
from a function
and here
okay so now we're going to go and take
those values so and went up and and so
delta direction and if we have a list
delta
jury pools idealists
we can attend to it so delta
hands
one point two three four
by-product
you can add a number on to it
and then if you say delta direction
we now have a list of one item on it
and we can attend again
negative nine point four
pickle barrel lesson that we have a
lesson keep adding on to as we go
through this
so he's are for a link to keep doubting
our numbers as we go through will team
up and
and we'll take our deed
and if we
scroll back up here a little bit we're
looking at
output this one the line grab from sort
of wrap our direction which is the zero
position in the first one
studies sub-zero
help with the space in their immaculate
more readable
and then we'll do the same thing for our
meters
apparent
and then that the
inward
say were number that is for
this guy
our distance
for position is that nearing
fossil
okay let's
say that
and let's give it a try and see it will
wrap
i know i had time we're gonna hit about
that
because they're something that we didn't
think about yet
which is why it's nice to serve the rate
code slowly as you go
sourcesafe this control x control that's
go back over here scroll beat down
and we need to reloaded again so
reloaded wonder to you
and now if we tried again within your
control or
wonder
some university rich that's a control
are
i think it should be a couple times this
for search and i i started looking nice
to have to go back to the streets
otherwise
we start getting a lot of commands
you're gonna have to look wave axa
c_r_ inside of my pipe bombs to control
our
and then you start taking what you want
some part of it
so i typed february
for wonder
and then you just keep getting control
are it will keep looking back through
history
and if you get frustrated with the
annual prime fitting for e_p_a_ controls
the at this time
from scratch
soviet control or
i found my old command
they're like
if you just start meeting here apis
back-and-forth because starr ending that
commands
and press enter
and you'll see that
america's beer because there's a
karen there
here's the command iran
and i appreciate you guys
what a typical python error message
looks like because it takes in time to
get used to be fair
there's a lot here it's kinda
overwhelming at first
yet different awesome
cooling delta is not to find
so if you look at your
jobs that they were
delta and and they've been here if you
had talked to dr incident dot vince
foster
now getting their message is the right
thing
yet humble different things opening and
so you had the differences
for ranging up
okay so you have a typographical error
sit-ups or ally and the msi in range
seeing this in the word and
so four heidi space in which is i a m
and they need to work under in english
and in unison whole right
we need to know reload
one expects it didn't leave of their
issue indication ears there
right above the twenty six
so on line sixteen over unlocked it says
has funny indentation
anti-fascist theory exceeding twitching
patience equipped with their first child
facilitation for him
staying up so that's a patent rhetoric
yes about experience in texas is mine
all right let's take a peek help
so this is that they're advantage i have
for many years and steering it coz it
has lots of problems
uh... most of which is mine
look at your wife so bye
students in new zealand
look at read that whole wine
and many of the end
diego
so i've traveled to code so much for
things like that jump right out at me
that's nothing that bike you guys are
going to your pickup emilie is just that
after twenty years your eyeballs parts
missing stuff quick
so it takes time to get used to seeing
this you don't have an error message
which was to have a disaster
how come it's working pocket for
that could be there
uh...
ciently parentheses again going on them
no that's where test
you had too many frens
so you were making a list that we have
one point in time
and sold
immature weston didn't really make a
you so you're not running that code
uh... you're hearing some of our son
below your reliving high-priced
here we go
see this year he reloaded out front
needs you the world
wonder
there we go
doing clever waged fair
cause trouble
invalid syntax
thank you wanna colin
after here
so let's take a look
i thought you had
watcher capitalization on iraq
you have a lower case that's here in the
capital that's their work eighteen
capital
are not the same is case sensitive
so let's take a peek at this in error
message windows icon you can see a lot
of these
and right now it's gonna look like
messy stuff that doesn't make a lot of
sense
and apcs
couple hundred of these
hopefully it'll mean a little bit more
to you
that you see something like this
it says
value a reverses the arabs reporting
does it mean that say all that much
and what is going to use its gonna walk
through your code and show you where was
expert thought that you were in the
article in shell
and to tell you you were in your wonder
too dot padi
inside of this function
as they show you draw the line twenty
two inside of this thing right here this
is the code that we wrote
so there's something wrong happening in
this line
inside of this
if you look here says user live pi
modules papon to sort this is not
something we worked to assist
that pipe raj module that
we refusing to someone else wrote
we're now looking into their coats
so we're going to see their code which
we don't know we've never seen it before
once you start seeing something like
that don't expect to recognize the code
or really want to go on there too but it
was to really really have to
so this says
okay stop looking
researching that his first run your
brain often say attack
and we go down here
and the bottom
value air come back if you see miramax
come here
and it's got some taxing
what went wrong in terms of what it pot
answers undefined inversely geographic
maybe you have the focal point
anybody have any idea what that is
your chickens should really obviously
it took me
that fifteen minutes of staring at a so
don't
field this is something you should get
what i think happens here is that if you
have two points at the same location so
we have
appointed right next to that centroid
it's so close that i think the direction
doesn't make any sense
so there at the same location or they're
exactly the opposite
poseidon world
so it's either at the same point
on the it costs out of the quote
and so direction doesn't make sense so
it freaks out and says i don't know what
to do
can wanted me to do something for you
i think that's probably the right answer
is if you don't know the direction as
you just tell the user
this function doesn't work here
typically you wouldn't have to stop the
war averages right in the middle of our
glasses from my point is that we'll be
right next to her
result so i have to keep you guys a
little bit about how to you
catch these kinds of infections
we're gonna learn about
and how to catch
problems and fix the list of girls this
is the cool thing about pipeline if
you're in senior portrait your coverages
blow up in their beauty and the game
but in python if something goes wrong
and you know i think that you can say
all go ahead and grab exception and i'm
gonna do the right thing for you
so i'll show you have to face it syntax
which she say's try
says what your attempted stuff in here
however you want the code you need to
protect
and then accept
and hear you could say the air this is
the big error that you're gonna catch
the if they value error here were two
essay
if we cn error we know what it was
and then
this is the code that you bright to
correct the problem
and so only if something here through
the mid section does this come get
called sis's yours for a fix up the
world and see if we can keep going
it turns out that a lot of times and
fight on
exceptions are way communicate what
we're
things that happen and they're not
always that bad
and usually know how to fix them
data files not found intel user
you gave me the raw file name i'll find
the file but names so you will fix it
there's usually a way that
and we can try a quick example see what
that looks like
so can say trying
kalo dah
and then there's a special function the
nominees called rates
if you find in your code that something
is that you can say hammer
throat infection and say i don't know
what to do
this kind of fun you can say someone
else's problem model fix this
secrets a raise
loops go ahead and try raids
and then we can have
another
line psychic four spaces to get there
we will
never jet
here sis's
doesn't get run because we've
raise an exception
and then accept as we're gonna catch
that problem
you know
so here we've got archrival off
things that were trying to do
they could go wrong
it they go around we're gonna run the
exception in here and we'll handle it
here and ever and go on after that
i think it'll make a little more sense
when you see it's actually using it in
the code one sweet right here
to catch that exception where the
pointer too close together and we
actually know what the answer they stand
in the king talent
so hit enter twice here
and what you see so we get different
hello
and we see below down here
the race gets called saying ups
wife is bad
something bad happens
we jumped out of the except that runs
the code that's in here for a
fingerprint that we don't care if it's
not a big deal
so let's use this concept in our code
and i hope
that this make sense what you see it
used
in our for loop
we're gonna try
fatality at the indentation to try it
here in michigan a streak of you max it
makes inventing a fight on a lot easier
so many control space
usc marks at the bottom
and would be a rookie down to cover
those three lines
and if you look at the end of the python
menu
there's this shift region right
patrol seek revenge
we can use this menu option if you get
back
invents the whole section by one more in
depth
so inside of that right
was the control came here
set up and i can hit tab here
as intense that new block but i wanna
actually backup for the except psychic
delete her back space there
you could say except
press enter it now intends for us
in our case
we know those two points are right next
to each other their distance is
basically zero
and the direction
we can make up any director of the
matter destruction of the me needing so
we'll just pick zero north of
resurrection
so we can say delta
append
and we'll just give it the number zero
stories that go ahead and say you know
what
it straight north we don't care delta
uh... apparent
and we do know that it's zero meters
away
so what are called now any time we get
one of these exceptions
we're lucky here because it
i know there's only one type of section
of embassies will have to get you can
see
anytime we have a problem when you say
you know what these points are at the
same location
let's go ahead and save it
ravenna reload
and if this works
we're gonna see a lot of stuff goes
going across the screen because it's
going to return
aren't so i'm afraid of my head enter
and i'm linda hope it works
and if it works you're gonna see a whole
on the list goes by
so it's were computer data
going going going
and there goes a lot numbers
not very fun as you know that was
provided but it means arco it's going
well
so now we need to capture those students
a direction
com account
equals
and then our function
so that try accepts
every time we have a problem we just
assume that that number those that point
was at the same location and we knew
what to do in that case so we did a
little fudge
tren cach can really be useful like if
you have a divide by zero casey a rapid
you if you know how to work through that
you can provide that information
checks that the divide by zero do the
right thing and get the code back on
track
familiar had to endure
and save thirty variables
uh... that's the plan your father
c_h_a_ the returned she deserved at the
c_i_a_ behind his head down there never
returned
and make sure the return you couldn't
idea in the eastern intensity tell on
that one
and now he backspace and what's your
support closes have more time back
and then
is showing you what's going on
today's return your dealt with her
yourself
so if you take a look at we're fine just
really can't see it
there's a return
that needs to be at the end
you have to stand up and what it's doing
here
after prints tends to be returned on
returns to tell tutor delta and that's
it
invalidates
skin pacts
so here you've got your x abt u missing
your white house
break here
you're missing here why average
so now that we have some data
that's actually useful
so now we have
direction and our m
wiggins they average
babar distances ten years
and uh... i have remembered
after a type of thing to do and p dot
because i didn't do that yes just by lab
surgeon legend like not stuck in my head
for n_p_r_ average
that gives us two point seventy five
years is the average distance from our
centroid
for a g_p_s_
so depending on what you're doing with
the g_p_s_ if you're trying to do
senator accuracy surveying with this
g_p_s_ here at a lot
if you're trying to navigate a vote
through a very large uh... coaching it's
great
we can also say meaning
between june and he probably
and then come that works
so zero point zero for summer exciting
because we knew we had points at work
the same location
but more interesting is max
it gets as bad as twenty two point eight
meters away
this g_p_s_
i want to look at the data stupid policy
was being a differential mo g_p_s_
i don't believe it
twenty meters for differential g_p_s_
near the coast is pretty
we have to go look at this g_p_s_ and
figure out if it's miss configured or
that's just
wine about being a differential
more important than just
looking at these numbers
is plotting it up and take a peek
so let's
map lautenberg imports
so that's going to get a truck
functions i hope
hyatt
what this is where i gained a shaky
ground because i used by lab so much
there is a pipeline to tap their to get
this list of options so don't
notice from this one this is what we
were not here
and then m
so hopefully
cross your fingers hit enter
and we see nothing
what was going on before he was in a
mode
where you want to show everything right
away and we have to know how to get
through it
to show
so we have to run the show command and
will now get a crack
services
samples with time
and the distance from that center point
in our
g_p_s_
terrible appoints
so that's nice
but we also maybe one of your i_q_
histogram them i feel the better way of
doing this data
since it's for a party in a sense of
here's our carol point we don't really
have a good sense of how much
sometime it's where so we can do a
histogram
with pride plots dot
to give that a shot
please at least one argument so question
mark
so the pipeline hist and then m
tells you
all the benefits making and doesn't
catch stuff
and here's tendons
now if you guys remember from
undergraduate statistics in math
histograms are kinda unstable
they really depend on the number of
things that you've got so let's try a
different over opinions
let's say bins equals
was had pretends that can
and according about this is intel you
clear the plot
y'all keep
getting
the plots on top each other so you can
keep seeing them
so you can see how your histogram
changes with the number of pins and it
really for showing you that
this is the same data for those
histograms have very different
so let's try a hundred
throughout starts giving initiate of
history everything is a sense of where
the points off
and quit acts
they get
so they needed uh... support coming
soviet spy plot people i peeled
dot plots
and then left for at the c_n_n_ m
magistrate pmcc
since they goes wearing off the screen
way too fast
here's that first import
that i did a plot
followed by a show
and i have crack and i want to get rid
of it so i clicked the except here
and nicer do my histograms down here
through history and the default is
tendons
so that they should give you a sense of
how to do some really simple graphs
and he can give you a sense of how the
debate is
before you go and do some really heavy
duty fiscal analysis
python has got
all kinds of siskel tools including he
can reach into the are cisco packaging
grab all of those tools
so you can do
spew kurtosis soon deviation fitting
there's tons of stuff you can do in here
with all sorts of different effects
so we've got a few more minutes
or make sure everyone gets the stuff
plotted
now click the acts to quit
and i think this is where previous
popular intractable box on top of the
acts
concedes that the accident pop wafts
close the window button
beethoven our thinking type paper
cuts in and out of the points
uh... for some reason it locks up
called for anime
haven't figured that out pile up doesn't
do that
dvds palm
that was me asking your help
so what that's doing a good tidy next
winter there's actually get wrong
because just asking for help them get
stuck
sos putting a comic character limit and
so i used to question mark
to ask for help
so carefully
he should be practicing with i fight on
and you'll see those for you histories
anytime you ask for help on something
you should see a complicated is the
question mark after anything
that's how we'll look at it
figuring on
wanted to
okay and now running
june import the plotting program
so from that bartlett important ipos
and gave higher plot dot plot
leprosy
and then m
and now i thought that show and two
persons
look up there at number
forty one
and then when you're done with that
euclid
the orange red affair
i found some big bucks a day
so on thursday party guys turn in your
logfile you've been keeping for this
class
i mentioned earlier in the class
separate state how i can't read
and so on thursday he'll be copping out
over the research tools server
yes shorter if you went back to a new
uh... go back in the lecture notes too
about what you were taught by pipe bomb
actually went
how disable aubrey content history
anything paste incurable apartment
kppm org o_ clock properly
arms
so you can create like uh...
apart from four four
in your notes indian in history and a
copy and paste then
shirt victims
here
own
your research tools of those unit
research tools
uh... do it's like to join of
yes it was a i think unpopular
rituals for the court you are interested
pls
subdued slash joining
u_n_ h
research
and there's you know yaa
to do this existed me
so if so is it that's the one thing if
you will just
happily create there's nobody there ages
give up your the one on parisian
and loser
history
using midterm
yeah thirty renewable hundreds he went
through that
so there's a couple different ways to do
it that he's one of suspect art history
space
and then senior
forty-five cancellation of the last
couple but you probably want all of them
about history
question mark
analog help-wanted
and see how you can do history
and one and two sidhu acumen get out of
that
and now to history space
one space forty six
or forty-five
mickey kantor
incidental if you scroll left up you'll
see all that
now lucky people of mice
c_q_ what does your sometimes it is
taking notes it really it's up to you
but they have to look at these notes
that i just what you think about the no
concept and
if you just give me entries with nothing
in there i'm actually okay with that
so it's what
what you think it's going to benefit you
know
the idea of the artistic have you guys
explore the idea of
taking on notes
and if you look at my along those i'd
take
thirty to forty thousand one of those
suggested
itself
the one i think that we
been trying to figure out how to
organize the class
use unlike material
caterpillar my suggestion for a living
with her realty of notes like that have
long dropbox into sink everywhere
anything that with my state we've got
history notes and
there's no i think i would love to show
you guys at this giant list of things
that would help in your research
and look good to teach this class for
two years three
two days a week
and i would not one of the material
so material things like that so
typically like if you're doing your self
a tree and stuff
that you've got
there's commands like find that what you
walk to retrieve point stuff we can
rates at the pipeline
investment research trees and stuff
and so you building at those notes
wherever you put them as long as it's
taxed season search
it just takes more than a couple
commands and
festival that kind of pushing us towards
bit by bit materials not yet covered
in a place
julius
yet as a couple different ways but if
you work with the prosecution do stuff
with my problem responsible who is but
there's also w x pipeline
he's pleased about it that's
for file
star
and why we typically do since you don't
have a fictional mins
kamini fictional file
thirty something like
maker
dot dot
for file
and get something like
c_p_
dog file
structure
out told susumu reduce so often that
on eats like every time it's different
like a location that
file
truly braces
dot
tvr
anywhere you want to ask form
it depends on the software see what it
takes yeah some of them
what and what is the one or more for cal
four characters
uh... so this is exactly the
what you're looking at very few that
bashing and he started i i font
soaring you've been that window urine
two levels of shell
and so do you use the bank to get back
to the bash